Okay, before we move further, it's
important to understand some of the
rules of HTML. While this isn't an HTML
course, I am going to go over just a few
of the basics. So, for example, one of
the rules is that everything must be
within the two HTML tags. So, the
opening HTML tag and the closing HTML
tag. If I open those up, you'll see I
have two other sets of tags. I've got
the head tags and the body tags. And I
can open up the head tags and see what's
inside of there.
and I can open up the body tag and see
what's inside of there. Um, all of these
tags are related and if we wanted to
describe how they were related, um, we
could come up with our own methodology
or we could use the one that's
standardly used. The one that's
standardly used is they use familial
terms to describe these. For example,
they say this header tag
is a sibling to this main tag. And why
do we say that they're siblings? Well,
they're both contained within the body
tag. If I close the body tag, they all
disappear. So header is related to main
and is related to footer. And how are
they related? Well, they're all on the
same level. So what we're going to do is
we're going to say they are all
siblings.
If we use sibling to describe
neighboring tags, then the tag that
contains them all would be a parent. So
we would say the body tag is the parent
of the header tag. The body tag is the
sibling of the other head tag. The body
tag is the child of the HTML tag. Um,
and in that way we can navigate through
this tree. So we could say um from the
header, go up to the parent, then go to
the sibling, the sibling of the body is
head,
and then look for the title tag. And we
could then navigate from header to title
using those words that I just described.
Um, and those are going to be really
helpful as we try and edit the HTML
page.